<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>DataDocks | Dock Scheduling Software on DataDocks</title><link>https://datadocks.com/</link><description>Recent content in DataDocks | Dock Scheduling Software on DataDocks</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://datadocks.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to get around the limitations of your WMS</title><link>https://datadocks.com/posts/how-to-get-around-limitations-warehouse-management-system/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://datadocks.com/posts/how-to-get-around-limitations-warehouse-management-system/</guid><description>How to get around the limitations of your Warehouse Management System The effects of the covid-19 pandemic have demonstrated some glaring vulnerabilities in global logistics. Many executives outside the operational realm had simply assumed that existing technology would be good enough to facilitate rational decision-making that could take into account what’s happening at every point along the supply chain, including in a crisis.
In reality, most operational decision-makers have little visibility outside their own domains.</description></item><item><title>Bring Tech Into Your Shipping and Receiving</title><link>https://datadocks.com/posts/bring-tech-into-your-logistics-department/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://datadocks.com/posts/bring-tech-into-your-logistics-department/</guid><description>Bring New Technology into Your Supply Chain A common line I hear from people is “I don’t have time…” This is probably one of my favourite lines to hear from people. This means you are either taking on too much work, managing your time inefficiently, or you are not delegating tasks appropriately - or all of the above. I’m a true believer in nothing is impossible; manage your time wisely and anything is possible.</description></item><item><title>Optimize Your Shipping Department</title><link>https://datadocks.com/posts/optimize-your-shipping-department/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://datadocks.com/posts/optimize-your-shipping-department/</guid><description>Every Logistics Department Could Use a Tune Up, Optimize Your Shipping In a lot of organizations the logistics is one of the last departments to get the attention of the management team. A lot of managers think “hey, these processes are working okay, no need to worry about it.” However, this is kind of a backwards way of thinking. Your logistics team is either the first or last people to see your product.</description></item></channel></rss>