<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>DataDocks | Dock Scheduling Software on DataDocks</title><link>https://datadocks.com/</link><description>Recent content in DataDocks | Dock Scheduling Software on DataDocks</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://datadocks.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to Align Warehouse KPIs to Your Company's Strategic Goals</title><link>https://datadocks.com/posts/warehouse-kpis/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://datadocks.com/posts/warehouse-kpis/</guid><description>The best warehouse is the one that most effectively helps the business reach its objectives.
There&amp;rsquo;s plenty of advice about which metrics are the most important for warehouses to track. But none of it matters if you&amp;rsquo;re not clear on what the business as a whole needs to achieve.
Once you have that, it&amp;rsquo;s fairly straightforward to loosely define a warehouse performance strategy:
Business Strategy Common Business KPI types Warehouse Strategy Financial Health Profitability Liquidity Inventory Turnover Return on Assets Reduce Costs: per period, per volume, or per order Governance CSR, ESG and DEI Structure &amp; Accountability Resilience &amp; Continuity Audit Accuracy Expand Reporting, Improve Safety &amp; Sustainability Growth Customer Acquisition Cost Sales Revenue Brand Awareness Headcount &amp; Asset Value Free Up Capacity, Be Ready to Scale Process &amp; System Performance Productivity &amp; Waste Project Success Rate Output Quality Capability Adopt New Technology and Build Digital Maturity Customer Satisfaction Churn Rate Net Promoter Score Customer Lifetime Value Perfect Order Rate Ship faster, in full and with thorough documentation Culture &amp; Effectiveness Employee Retention Participation &amp; Satisfaction Profit per Employee Performance of Individuals Improve employee quality of life and learning opportunities.</description></item><item><title>How Shippers &amp; Receivers Are Eliminating Detention and Demurrage Fees</title><link>https://datadocks.com/posts/how-shippers-and-receivers-are-eliminating-detention-and-demurrage-fees/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://datadocks.com/posts/how-shippers-and-receivers-are-eliminating-detention-and-demurrage-fees/</guid><description>Detention charges levied by carriers for loading delays are painful. During the supply chain chaos of 2021, many companies discovered they can be unpredictable enough to present a business risk. But an increasing number of facilities have found a way to completely avoid incurring these costs.
Shippers and receivers should understand that driver detention fees are not a profit center for carriers. Every party involved in logistics would prefer to run on time.</description></item><item><title>How to Reduce Warehouse Turnover and Retain Your Best People</title><link>https://datadocks.com/posts/how-to-reduce-warehouse-turnover/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://datadocks.com/posts/how-to-reduce-warehouse-turnover/</guid><description>A shortage of experienced warehouse staff exposes your business to hidden risk. What starts as a gradual build-up of congestion can quickly turn into logistics gridlock. Sooner or later you have painful problems to deal with, like incomplete inventory, missing goods and furious customers.
Supply chain companies must become more desirable employers. In short, that means offering better opportunities for advancement. Reinforcing that with superior on-the-job quality of life adds up to a powerful incentive to stay.</description></item><item><title>What Is a Supply Chain Center of Excellence?</title><link>https://datadocks.com/posts/what-is-a-supply-chain-center-of-excellence/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://datadocks.com/posts/what-is-a-supply-chain-center-of-excellence/</guid><description>Where did &amp;lsquo;Centers of Excellence&amp;rsquo; come from originally? The expression has been used informally since the 19th century. But in the 1960s the U.S. government was concerned that a small number of universities were being awarded almost all of the research contracts from the Department of Defense, resulting in many of the country&amp;rsquo;s best scientists flocking to a few coastal cities.
To remedy this, Project Themis sought to establish centers of excellence at colleges throughout the country.</description></item><item><title>What Is Dock Scheduling? Everything You Need to Know About This Powerful Optimization Process</title><link>https://datadocks.com/posts/what-is-dock-scheduling/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://datadocks.com/posts/what-is-dock-scheduling/</guid><description>At its most basic level, dock scheduling is the process of optimizing and automating dock door and yard schedules.
But there&amp;rsquo;s so much more to it than that.
Because the truth is the right dock scheduling system can completely transform your operations and drastically improve your traffic flow.
And in this guide, I&amp;rsquo;ll show you exactly how dock scheduling can change everything for your warehouse. A Deep Dive Into Dock Scheduling Does your facility have lots of traffic only on Mondays and Fridays?</description></item><item><title>Machine Learning in Supply Chains</title><link>https://datadocks.com/posts/machine-learning-in-supply-chains/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://datadocks.com/posts/machine-learning-in-supply-chains/</guid><description>The most mature applications of 2022 Executive Summary Logistics and manufacturing leaders are bombarded with abstract visions for how A.I. and other leading-edge technologies might one day improve their business.
Although the theoretical possibilities really are immense, the number of machine learning solutions that can be integrated into the daily operations of a typical facility and have a tangible impact and predictable R.O.I. is still small.
Identifying these mature services demands time-intensive research, and this is not an industry with an excess of spare time for its executives.</description></item><item><title>How to get around the limitations of your WMS</title><link>https://datadocks.com/posts/how-to-get-around-limitations-warehouse-management-system/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://datadocks.com/posts/how-to-get-around-limitations-warehouse-management-system/</guid><description>How to get around the limitations of your Warehouse Management System The effects of the covid-19 pandemic have demonstrated some glaring vulnerabilities in global logistics. Many executives outside the operational realm had simply assumed that existing technology would be good enough to facilitate rational decision-making that could take into account what’s happening at every point along the supply chain, including in a crisis.
In reality, most operational decision-makers have little visibility outside their own domains.</description></item><item><title>Bring Tech Into Your Shipping and Receiving</title><link>https://datadocks.com/posts/bring-tech-into-your-logistics-department/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://datadocks.com/posts/bring-tech-into-your-logistics-department/</guid><description>Bring New Technology into Your Supply Chain A common line I hear from people is “I don’t have time…” This is probably one of my favourite lines to hear from people. This means you are either taking on too much work, managing your time inefficiently, or you are not delegating tasks appropriately - or all of the above. I’m a true believer in nothing is impossible; manage your time wisely and anything is possible.</description></item><item><title>Optimize Your Shipping Department</title><link>https://datadocks.com/posts/optimize-your-shipping-department/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://datadocks.com/posts/optimize-your-shipping-department/</guid><description>Every Logistics Department Could Use a Tune Up, Optimize Your Shipping In a lot of organizations the logistics is one of the last departments to get the attention of the management team. A lot of managers think “hey, these processes are working okay, no need to worry about it.” However, this is kind of a backwards way of thinking. Your logistics team is either the first or last people to see your product.</description></item></channel></rss>